Guide to the John Russell Mason papers, 1931-1981 MS0242.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Library exhibits under J.R. Mason as curator, 1948-1966; MS0242 Series 5; 4 Linear feet
  - #159 American Drawing - Collection Bruce Howe, undated (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - #160 GWU Art Club - 16th Annual Show, undated (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - #161 Paintings and Prints - from the university collection, undated (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - #162 Photographs by Russell Jones, undated (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - #163 English Watercolors, undated (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - #164 American Drawings, undated (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - #165 Honduran Art, undated (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - #166 William F. Walter, undated (Box 22, Folder 27)
- Papers, photographs, and ephemera, 1931-1981; MS0242 Series 6; 3 Linear feet
  This series consists of correspondence, photographs, programs, and ephemera. Topics include University colors, the Houdon statue and the U.S. Grant collection. They range in date from 1931-1981.
  - Photographs and ephemeral material, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Library exhibit records on 3x5 index cards, by number and title, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - John Russell Mason - life, 1965-1981 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Library correspondence and memoranda, 1932-1939 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Library correspondence and memoranda, 1947-1960 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Library correspondence and memoranda, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Library correspondence and memoranda, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from job applicants, 1963-1964 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Theses and dissertation written by GW students in 1963 - list (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Exhibits, 1956-1964 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - GW portrait/art collection - memos and correspondence, 1929-1964 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - GW portrait/art collection - Federal Storage Company, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - GW portrait/art collection - Veerhoff Galleries, 1962-1963 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Lisner Auditorium mural done by Augustus Vincent Tack, 1944-1952 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Houdon (replica) statue of George Washington - correspondence, 1931-1941 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - University colors (Buff and Blue) - correspondence and samples, 1951-1957 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - University colors (Buff and Blue), Munsell Color Company, Inc. - correspondence and charts, 1956-1958 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - U.S. Grant Memorial Room and Collection - correspondence, 1950-1964 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Notes and correspondence on George Washington University history, 1938-1950 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, etc., 1934-1964 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Dedication of the John Russell Mason room in the Gelman Library - program, exhibit, clippings, etc., 1965-1974 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Dedication of the John Russell Mason room in the Gelman Library - scrapbook of photos and guest book, 03/09/1974 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Scrapbook of Mason's cruise on the S.S. Constitution, 02/1968-05/1968 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Mason's personal correspondence, etc., 1948-1974 (Box 25, Folder 22)